Previously on Revolution...
末世革命 前情提要
- Why'd you do it? - 'Cause we needed him and you asked me to.
- 你為什麼這麼做? - 因為我們需要他 因為你要求我做
- You have to tell me where my son is. - One thing at a time.
- 你必須告訴我 我的兒子在哪兒 - 一件一件地來
You set off a bomb in my town.
你在我鎮上放了個炸彈
Your job is to keep our town healthy and compliant,
你的工作是保證我們的鎮 健康和服從
unless you're not a loyal American.
除非你不是個忠誠的美國人
You can't fix him. It's the training.
你救不了他了 這就是訓練的作用
You cut him loose, he will kill us both.
你放了他 他就會殺了我們兩個
You were so worried about trusting my son,
你之前還擔心我不信任我兒子
when you should've been worried about trusting me.
你該擔心的是該不該信任我
You said your husband was Patriot high command?
你說你丈夫是愛國者的高層?
- What do you want? - Where is the old ball and chain?
- 你想要什麼? - 你丈夫在哪兒?
I'd like to pick your brain about the nanotech.
我想聽你談談納米科技
He's already onto the bodies.
他已經在調查屍體了
Aaron, it's only a matter of time before Horn is onto you.
Aaron Horn遲早會盯上你的
So where are they?
那他們在哪兒?
I did not want to be right about this.
我也不希望我是對的
He's one of them.
他是他們中的一員
We got to get Aaron out of here.
我們得把Aaron救出去
I'm Aaron Pittman! I'll come quietly! Just leave her alone!
我是Aaron Pittman! 我會跟你們走! 放開她!
Aaron, you have got to tell me how you do that.
Aaron 你告訴我你是怎麼做到的
You don't have to be afraid of him,
你不用怕他
but it's not him you're afraid of, is it?
你害怕的不是他 對吧?
Why don't you tell me what's going on, please?
你們誰能告訴我發生了什麼事嗎?
****
威洛比 公園與遊憩部 市游泳館
Where's Horn?
Horn在哪兒?
I haven't seen the son of a bitch in a while,
我很久沒見那個混蛋了
but I'm pretty sure you know where he's holed up.
但你肯定知道他藏在哪兒
He's working.
他在工作
Always working.
總是在工作
Working where?
在哪兒工作?
You have no idea who you're dealing with.
你根本不知道自己是在和誰打交道
Is that right?
是嗎?
Horn's looking for you.
Horn正在找你
He's got men everywhere looking for you...
他四處派人找你...
and her...
和她...
and Pittman.
還有Pittman
and once he finds you...
一旦他找到你...
know what he's gonna do?
知道他會怎麼做嗎?
Of course I do.
我當然知道
That's why I'm gonna find him first.
所以我要先找到他
So let's try this one more time.
那我們再試一次
Where is he?
他在哪兒?
I know, I know.
我知道 我知道
The bombing rocked all of us.
那個炸彈嚇到了所有人
It was a tragedy and an act of cowardice, plain and simple.
這是一場悲劇 說白了 就是懦夫的行為
And, folks... We now know who was behind the bombing...
各位... 我們現在知道 炸彈背後的罪魁禍首了...
the man who stood amongst us and called himself Stu Redman.
就是我們中間那個自稱Stu Redman的人
But his real name is Miles Matheson.
但他的真名叫Miles Matheson
You may have heard of him...
你們或許聽說過他...
General Miles Matheson of the Monroe Republic.
Monroe共和國的Miles Matheson將軍
Now, we have reason to believe he was acting in retaliation
我們有理由相信 他這是出於報復
for the execution of his former leader... Sebastian Monroe,
為的是他之前的領導... Sebastian Monroe的死刑
and he didn't act alone.
他並不是獨自行動
He had an accomplice... Aaron Pittman.
他有一名共犯... Aaron Pittman
Uh, yeah.
是啊
Matheson and Pittman pulled the wool over our eyes, yours and mine.
Matheson和Pittman欺騙了我們大家
My daughter also came to town with them.
我的女兒也是和他們一起來到鎮上的
She was troubled psychologically. Some of you know that.
她出現了心理問題 你們有些人知道
She had nothing to do with any of this.
她與這一切毫無關係
She and my granddaughter are victims.
她和我的外孫女都是受害者
They were manipulated by these men.
受到了這些人的操控
So, please, if you see them, report it to a U.S. officer.
所以我求大家 如果看見了她們 向美國官員報告
I'm begging you, help me find them.
我求你們 幫我找到她們
I just want my family safe.
我只想要家人平安
They said they'd meet us here, they'll meet us here.
他們說在這裡跟我們會面 就會說到做到
Well, I got news for you, stay puft.
我有消息要告訴你 驅鬼者
There might have been a change of plan.
計劃或許有變
What change of plan?
怎麼個變法?
In that this plan has gone to hell.
變化就是這個計劃完蛋了
Those Patriot sons of bitches were waiting for you.
那些混蛋愛國者正在等你
And we don't know what happened.
我們不清楚發生了什麼
We don't know if Miles can even get out of town or if he's still alive.
我們不知道Miles能否出城 甚至不知道他是生是死
We're gonna wait right here like Miles told us to.
我們要像Miles叮囑的一樣 老實在這等著
Whoa, okay, okay. Just don't light me on fire or anything.
哇 好吧 好吧 只要別把我給點著了
Who's that?
那是誰?
Nobody. Just some intel.
沒誰 就是問些情報
What's it like out there?
外面什麼情況?
It's not good.
不怎麼好
Truman told everyone who Miles really is.
Truman告訴了每個人Miles的真實身份
Said that Miles is the one that blew up the building and that he's the terrorist.
說是Miles炸了那棟樓 說他是個恐怖分子
Did you see your grandfather?
看見你外公了嗎?
Charlie?
Charlie?
Yeah.
看見了
Look, mom, we got to find a way out of town now.
聽著 媽媽 我們現在得想辦法出城
- Not yet. - Why not? Aaron's waiting for us.
- 還沒到時候 - 為什麼? Aaron在等我們
This is for Aaron, trust me.
這是為了Aaron好 相信我
They will never give up.
他們是不會放棄的
They will never stop looking for him unless we kill Horn first.
他們不會停止找尋他 除非我們先殺了Horn
They're calling us terrorists.
他們叫我們恐怖分子
Just you wait.
那就等著瞧吧
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents
-=伊甸園美劇 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=伊甸園字幕站 http://ytet.org=- 榮譽出品 本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業途徑
Sync: 有志青年
-=YTET-伊甸園字幕組=- 翻譯: Echo Zzinc 安靜 acothall 校對: 三三Diane 尉遲逸 時間軸: 有志青年
<font color=#29F6E5>Revolution.S02E08
末世革命 第二季 第8集
****
愛國者地區前哨
Hold it right there.
待那兒別動
Tom Neville from the Savannah camp.
我是Tom Neville 來自薩凡納營區
I'm here to see commander Roger Allenford.
我來見Roger Allenford指揮官
State your business.
說明你的來由
Just... give him this.
把這個給他就好
Tell him...
告訴他...
I only speak to him.
我只和他談
Those real?
是真的嗎?
A little privacy, gentlemen.
讓我們單獨談一下 各位
Is she alive?
她還活著嗎?
Yes, sir.
是的 長官
She is.
她還活著
Where is she?
她在哪?
Tied up... safe, hidden.
被捆綁著... 很安全 很隱蔽
You've got a lot of balls coming into my office
你真夠有種的 居然敢來我辦公室
and telling me you've got my wife captive.
告訴我你監禁了我妻子
With all due respect, sir,
恕我直言 長官
your wife is an enemy of the United States of America.
你妻子是美國的敵人
I figured that you were a good Patriot.
我知道你是個愛國者
Am I wrong?
難道我說錯了?
She's guilty of sedition.
她因叛亂獲罪
She should be punished.
她該遭受懲罰
So why not bring her in?
那為何不把她帶來?
My guess is that you have
我猜你現在
a dark and stormy cloud over your head,
頭上陰雲密佈
over an otherwise spotless career.
影響著你毫無瑕疵的事業
I mean, your wife is a traitor.
你妻子是個叛徒
People have to be whispering
人們一定在竊竊私語
whether or not you were pillow-talking,
你們有無枕邊密語
whether or not any of it rubbed off on you.
這些有沒有影響到你
But if you brought your wife in by yourself,
但如果你親自帶著你妻子
delivered her unto justice,
將她交付法律
that would solve all of your problems, wouldn't it?
你的問題都迎刃而解了吧?
Turn that rain into sunshine.
扭轉局勢
And why would you do this for me?
你為什麼要為我這樣做?
Honestly? I'm ambitious.
說實話? 我很有野心
And I think there's value
而我覺得
in being friends with a man like you.
和你這樣的人交友很有價值
So, Commander...
所以 指揮官...
would you like to come and see the missus?
你想來看看你的太太嗎?
****
愛國者總部 德州 威洛比
I thought these people trusted you.
我以為那些人相信你
I thought you were their beloved Dr. Porter.
我以為你是他們敬愛的Porter醫生
Someone will know where Pittman is... I'll find him.
總有人知道Pittman在哪... 我會找到他
Do you know what'll happen to your daughter if you don't?
你知道要是你找不到 你女兒會怎樣嗎?
Or your granddaughter?
或者你外孫女?
Threatening me won't find him any faster.
威脅我也不能讓我早點找到他
Someone knows something.
肯定有人知道些什麼
How about we get everyone Pittman knows,
不如我們把Pittman認識的每個人
march them into town square, and start executing them?
都帶到廣場上 一個個拷問?
I bet they'll talk then.
我發誓他們會開口的
I have put a hell of a lot of time into managing this town.
我可是花了大力氣去管理好這個鎮
- We have a plan. - Right, the plan...
- 我們有個計劃 - 對 計劃
taking town after town.
佔領一個又一個城鎮
And how many years until you take the whole continent?
你們拿下整個大陸要花多少年?
If I get my hands on Pittman and figure out what makes him tick,
如果我抓到Pittman 找到讓他活著的東西
we take everything in months.
不出幾個月我們就能佔領所有的
That's all.
就這樣吧
Here, I found this.
給 我找到這個
What is that?
那是什麼?
What is this, food?
這是什麼 吃的嗎?
People used to think so, yeah.
人們以前也這麼覺得
I know you're angry,
我知道你很生氣
and I'm not apologizing for him.
但我不會為他道歉
But you don't know why grandpa did what he did.
但你不知道外公為什麼這樣做
He sold us out. He works for them.
他出賣了我們 他為他們賣命
Yeah, I get it. You hate him for it.
我知道 你為此憎恨他
You don't?
你不恨嗎?
No.
不
Well, you're a better person than me.
那你比我善良
No, I'm not.
不 我不善良
I hated you for a long time
我恨了你很長一段時間
for abandoning Danny and me...
因為你拋棄了我和Danny...
for killing Nora.
因為你殺了Nora
That's not fair.
這不公平
This is different.
這不一樣
All I'm saying is hating you was the easy part.
而且 憎恨你還算是簡單的
But letting it go?
但要釋懷?
That's hard.
那就難了
It's like EPCOT East Berlin out there.
外面像是東柏林主題公園一樣
They have dogs.
他們養了狗
When the hell did they get dogs?
他們從哪找來的狗?
You find the place?
你找到那地方了?
The guy's intel was legit.
那人的情報是真的
Basement of the old paper factory.
舊造紙廠的地下室
Definitely their H.Q.
肯定是他們的總部
Is there any way to get in there, drop some kind of device?
有什麼方法可以進去嗎 扔點什麼裝置?
Not gonna be easy.
肯定不容易
Place is sealed up tighter than a drum.
這地方封得嚴嚴實實
And, uh, Rachel, the...
另外 Rachel...
there's something else. I... I saw Truman walking in.
還有些事... 我看見Truman走進去了
Good. Two birds, one stone.
很好 一石二鳥
Walking in with Gene.
是和Gene一起進去的
You should try to sleep.
你該試著睡一下
You haven't said a word all day. Come on...
你一整天都沒說話了
talk to me.
和我說話
Did you kill Carl?
是你殺了Carl嗎?
What?
什麼?
Did you kill my husband?
是你殺了我丈夫嗎?
The way he died,
他死的方式
the fire in the car,
車裡的火
it was always strange.
都那麼奇怪
- He hit me. - Oh, my...
- 他先打我的 - 噢 天啊
oh, God.
天啊
Oh, God, Aaron.
天哪 Aaron
I got angry, and I couldn't control it.
我很生氣 失去了控制
You know I can't control it.
你知道我無法控制的
You lied to me.
你騙了我
You murdered him, and you slept in my bed...
你殺了他 卻還睡在了我的床上...
and you lied about it.
你還說了謊
I'm sorry.
對不起
I didn't know how to explain it.
我不知道怎麼跟你解釋
I've had enough liars in my life.
我遇到過太多的騙子了
- Cynthia... - Just leave me alone.
- Cynthia... - 離我遠點兒
I need to think.
我需要想想
What?
怎麼了?
I always dreamed of cooking with my daughter,
我一直夢想和我的女兒一起做飯
just not like this.
只不過不是這樣子
You sure this stuff is safe to carry?
你確信這東西能安全攜帶?
Separately they're fine.
它們分開後是安全的
But drop this with this down an air shaft into a locked up basement?
但是把這個和這個通過通風井 扔進一個鎖著的地下室?
The gas will kill Horn and everyone else inside.
毒氣會殺死Horn和裡面的其他人
So when the time comes to do this,
那什麼時候去做這件事
what if grandpa's there?
要是外公在那裡怎麼辦?
Let's just hope that he's not.
那希望他不在那裡吧
Okay, but if he is,
好吧 但是假如他在的話
you're not gonna go through with it, right?
你就不會這麼做的 對吧?
Mom?
媽?
Hey.
嘿
Where the hell are you going?
你要去哪裡?
You're just gonna leave us?
你要離開我們?
Look, if Miles was coming, he would've been here by now.
聽著 要是Miles會來 他早到這裡了
I'm gonna go find him.
我去找到他
And what if they find us?
要是他們找到我們了呢?
All right, just... just hold on, hold on.
好 只是... 等等 等等
We wouldn't last three days without you.
沒有你 我們活不過三天
You think three?
你還想三天?
Look, Miles has got some information that I need, someone I need to find.
聽著 Miles有我需要找的某個人的信息
I held up my end of the bargain.
我完成了我該做的
Now it's his turn...
現在輪到他了...
that's if he's even alive.
要是他還活著的話
You they won't kill.
他們不會殺了你
Me on the other hand...
我就不一樣了...
What?
什麼?
- What the hell are you doing? - Aaron!
- 你要幹嘛? - Aaron!
- Aaron, help! - Cynthia!
- Aaron 救命! - Cynthia!
Help!
救命!
Aaron!
Aaron!
****
電力消失前18年
Dad.
爸
- I will fear no evil for thou art with me. - Dad...
- 你與我同在 我將不再害怕邪惡 - 爸...
She's not getting any better.
她沒有好轉
She will.
會好的
God won't take her from me.
上帝不會把她從我身邊帶走的
What if there's something more that we could do for her?
要是我們還能為她做些什麼的話?
I'm praying as hard as I know how.
我會盡我所能努力為她禱告
Gary's father is a doctor.
Gary的爸爸是個醫生
Maybe he could come and see her.
也許他能來看看她
- He... he could... - He could what?\
- 他... 他能... - 他能幹嘛?
We cannot control the lord's will.
我們不能控制上帝的意志
Now, you know that.
你知道的
Now come pray with me, boy.
孩子 來跟我一起禱告
The lord is my Shepherd.
上帝是我的引導者
I shall not want.
我不想
We know that through you...
我們知道通過你...
Oh, no.
不是吧
She can't.
她不能這麼做
It's her decision to make.
是她自己做的決定
Dr. Porter, what are you doing here?
Porter醫生 你在這兒幹嘛?
We have the doctor to thank for finding you.
多虧醫生我們才能找到你們
Searching the boatyard was his idea.
搜索船塢是他的主意
Gene?
Gene?
Horn, let her go. Please...
Horn 放她走...
she's... she's got nothing to do with it. Please.
她... 她跟這一點關係都沒有 求求你
I'm sorry. I need insurance, Aaron.
不好意思 我需要保險 Aaron
Can't have one of your pyrotechnic displays.
不能讓你的煙火在這兒出現
As long as you cooperate, she'll be fine.
只要你合作 她就安全
You son of a bitch.
你個混蛋
Let her go. Let her go.
放開她 放開她
Cynthia, I'm sorry.
Cynthia 對不起
I'm sorry.
對不起
Aaron's inside.
Aaron在裡面
****
電力消失前18年
Dad?
爸爸?
What have you done, Calvin?
你幹了什麼 Calvin?
Gary's father gave them to me.
Gary爸爸給我的
I didn't want her to die.
我不想她死
Well, she died because of you.
她因你而死
You prayed for a miracle.
你祈禱奇跡
But there are no miracles.
但是沒有奇跡
Please, do anything you want to me.
你可以對我做任何事情
Just please let her go.
求求你 放她走
There.
來吧
That should keep you nice and relaxed.
會讓你覺得很好 很輕鬆
They tell me you came back from the dead, Aaron...
他們告訴我你死而復生 Aaron...
2 1/2 hours without a heartbeat.
兩個半小時沒有心跳
That would make you a modern-day Lazarus, wouldn't it?
你就是現代的麻風乞丐拉撒路?
That is, if you believed in that sort of thing.
要是你相信這些事情的話
So what say we start by seeing how resilient your body really is.
我們先來看看你的身體到底有多彈性
You're free to go, doctor.
你可以走了 醫生
I'm staying.
我要留在這
If you're going to hurt him, I want to be here to help him.
如果你要傷害他 我想留在這裡幫他
How do we know pain isn't an important part of it?
誰說疼痛不重要呢?
No, you did your part bringing him here. Thank you.
不 你把他帶來完成任務了 多謝
And as promised,
我保證
as long as your daughter doesn't look for any more trouble,
只要你女兒不再來找麻煩
I won't go looking for her.
我就不會去找她
Now, doctor.
走吧 醫生
****
北卡羅來納州 格蘭登
Jason, please. Please...
Jason 求你了 求你了...
just let me go.
放我走吧
Why are you doing this?
你為什麼要這麼做?
Is it because your father's telling you to? Huh?
因為你父親讓你這麼做? 是嗎?
Shut up.
閉嘴
You always follow the man's orders?
你總是聽從那人的命令嗎?
I said shut up.
我說了閉嘴
He let you get shipped off to that reeducation center.
他無視你被送到那個重組中心
He didn't try to stop it. He didn't say a word.
他都沒試著阻止 一句話都沒說
You know, he doesn't give a damn about you, and you just...
他一點都不關心你 而你...
Jason...
Jason...
you're not fully deprogrammed, are you?
你還沒被完全重組 對嗎?
Not completely...
還不完全...
not all the way.
還不徹底
How much further?
還有多遠?
Just up ahead.
就在前面
Do we have a problem?
有什麼問題嗎?
Did you hurt her?
你有沒有傷害她?
I wondered if something like this might happen.
我就在想這種事兒會不會發生
You're still sweet on the woman.
你還在乎那個女人
Well, first thing you need to know, I have a man on her.
首先你得知道 我派人正看著她
You try walking in there without me, it'll be a short reunion.
你要不和我一起進去 只能是見上一面而已
So how about we put the gun down?
何不把槍放下呢?
No, this is what's gonna happen.
不 你要這麼做
You're gonna take me in there, and you're gonna let my wife go.
你要帶我進去 然後放我老婆走
And then? What?
然後呢? 什麼?
You two run off together, escape like two star-crossed teens?
你們倆像對苦命鴛鴦一起跑掉嗎?
Boy, she must be worth it.
天吶 她一定值得你這麼做
She must give it to you good and sweet.
她一定給了你甜美回憶
Who the hell do you think you're talking to?
你以為你在跟誰說話?
I thought I was talking to a man with his head on straight.
我以為我在跟個頭腦清醒的人說話
If I bring her back...
如果我帶她回去...
- they'll kill her. - You cut her loose and run off,
- 他們會殺了她的 - 你放了她一起逃跑
they'll hunt you down and kill you both.
他們會追到你們把你們都殺了
How far do you think you're gonna make it
你以為憑你柔弱的手和精良的工藝
with your soft hands and your fine art?
能撐多久?
Be realistic.
現實點吧
Your wife went rogue without a single thought
你老婆叛變時都沒考慮
of what it might do to you or your son.
這會給你和你兒子帶來什麼後果
And if the boy has two traitor parents,
如果你兒子有一對叛徒父母的話
what do you think they're gonna do to him?
你覺得他們會怎麼對他?
The only question is,
唯一的問題是
what side of this are you gonna land on?
你到底要站在哪邊?
Charlie?
Charlie?
What the hell are you still doing in town?
你們怎麼還在小鎮上?
- You should be miles from here. - We can't.
- 你們應該離開這裡 - 不行
Aaron's our family.
Aaron是我們的家人
How'd they find him, Gene?
他們是怎麼找到他的 Gene?
I found him.
是我找到他的
And what's Horn doing with him?
Horn要對他做什麼?
I don't know.
我不知道
He's still alive... for now.
他還活著... 暫時
Grandpa, how could you?
外公 你怎麼可以這麼做?
They were gonna kill you if I didn't.
如果我不這麼做 他們就會殺了你們
What else was I supposed to do?
我還能怎麼做?
How about the right thing?
怎麼不做正確的事?
How about everything that you taught me?
做你教過我的所有事?
Okay. We're gonna get Aaron out of there,
好了 我們要把Aaron救出去
and you are gonna help.
你要幫我們
There's nothing I can do.
我幫不了你們
You can't get in. It's too late.
你們進不去的 太晚了
- And whose fault is that? - I was trying to keep you safe.
- 這又是誰的錯? - 我是要保護你的安全
Really?
真的嗎?
By lying to me?
就通過騙我?
By letting me think that I was crazy?
讓我以為我瘋了嗎?
How was that supposed to help?
這怎麼能是幫助我?
Your mother...
你母親...
died of an awful disease.
死於可怕的疾病
There was nothing I could do except watch her waste away.
我只能眼睜睜地看著她死去
And suddenly...
突然...
I had a chance to save everybody.
我有機會救每一個人
They gave me medicine.
他們能給我藥
No one else had to die like she did.
不必有人像她那樣死去了
I didn't realize who they were until it was too late.
我發現他們的真面目時已經太晚了
But, Rachel...
但是 Rachel...
it's too late.
太晚了
You rolled over.
你叛變了
You helped them.
你去幫助他們
You've never done a bad thing for a good reason?
你就從沒出於好意而做錯事嗎?
What about you, Miles?
你呢 Miles?
Dad...
爸爸...
how am I ever supposed to forgive you for this?
我怎麼能原諒你呢?
You're not.
你不用
I don't want it.
我也不奢望
If keeping you alive...
如果讓你活著...
means you hate me, then you just hate me.
就意味你會恨我 那你就恨吧
But for God's sake, run.
不過看在上帝份上 逃吧
Run.
逃吧
I know you all are in there!
我知道你們都在裡面!
You got one minute to surrender yourselves and come on out,
你們有一分鐘投降走出來
or we're coming in.
不然我們就進去了
Get them out, Gene, or else this ends bloody.
把他們帶出來 Gene 不然讓你們死得難看
- You son of a bitch. - I didn't know, I swear.
- 你個混蛋 - 我真不知道 我發誓
Look... I can...
聽著... 我可以...
let me stay behind.
讓我留下
Maybe I can buy you a couple of minutes.
沒準我能給你們爭取幾分鐘
Please.
求你們了
No.
不
You have to come with us.
你得和我們一起走
He's coming with us.
他要和我們一起走
Prepare to fire.
準備開槍
What is this, Gene?
這是搞什麼 Gene?
Where are they?
他們在哪裡?
Horn said he was gonna leave my daughter alone.
Horn說他不會再找我女兒麻煩
And he will.
他會的
But Miles Matheson bombed the town, remember?
但Miles Matheson炸了城鎮 記得嗎?
Now, you hand him over,
現在 你把他交出來
and your daughter walks free.
你的女兒可以儘管走
I heard that one before, Ed.
我以前就聽過這句話 Ed
It's the truth.
這是真話
Any one of you takes a step forward toward that building, this man dies.
你們有一個人朝這個房子走一步 我就殺了他
Big mistake here, Gene.
你這是在犯大錯誤 Gene
I've made worse.
我犯過更大的錯誤
Go, damn it!
上 該死!
Unbelievable.
難以置信
Why you, Aaron?
為什麼是你 Aaron?
The nanites in your body are behaving in a highly
納米機器人在你身體裡
individual way, repairing your cells,
用一種高度自治的方式修復你的細胞
oxygenating your blood.
給你的血液補氧
But why?
但是為什麼?
Why only you?
為什麼只有你?
I have no idea.
我不知道
You think of me as your enemy.
你把我當成你的敵人
But we're partners now.
但我們現在是搭檔
You know, my father believed there was
我父親相信
a magic, invisible power all around us,
在我們身邊有一種看不見的神奇力量
and if he prayed hard enough,
如果他足夠努力地祈禱
it would grant him a miracle.
就會賜給他奇跡
He was a horrible, stupid man
他是個可怕的蠢男人
who based his whole life on a fairy tale.
把他的整個人生建立在童話故事上
But it's ironic.
但很諷刺的是
Turns out he was right...
結果他是對的...
sort of.
算是吧
There is an invisible power that can save people.
有一種無形的力量能拯救人
It just doesn't come from heaven, that's all.
只不過不是來自天堂
But I have to admit,
但我不得不承認
it is, in its own way,
而是以自己的方式
a miracle.
是個奇跡
You're gonna teach me how to use it.
你要教我怎麼利用這種力量
I can't.
我不能
I don't know how.
我不知道怎麼做
Then we'll figure it out together.
那我們一起弄清楚
It's important.
這很重要
I have a tumor growing in my brain,
我腦子里長了個腫瘤
and the symptoms are getting worse.
症狀越來越嚴重
And I'd lost all hope.
我已經喪失了所有的希望
Then I heard about you.
然後我聽說了你的事
Aaron...
Aaron...
I need you to deliver me that miracle.
我需要你把那種奇跡傳遞給我
And I believe that you can.
而且我相信你可以
Jason!
Jason!
Easy, boy.
放鬆 兒子
Everything's under control.
一切都在掌控之中
Roger.
Roger
Justine.
Justine
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
對不起 真的很對不起
Writing that letter...
寫那封信...
was stupid.
很蠢
You knew how they would react.
你知道他們會作何反應
What they did to Max, to our baby boy...
他們對我們的寶貝兒子Max做的事...
I didn't want them to do that to anyone else.
我不想讓他們對其他人再那麼做
You know how much trouble you're in now...
你知道你現在惹了多少麻煩...
how much trouble we're both in because of you?
因為你 我們兩個有多少麻煩?
I'm sorry.
對不起
You got to stay clearheaded about this.
你要對這件事保持頭腦清醒
Roger, this is a dangerous man.
Roger 這是一個危險的人
You can kill them both, and we can run.
你可以殺了他們 然後我們逃走
Where?
去哪裡?
Huh? Where? Where can we go?
嗯? 去哪裡? 我們能逃向哪裡?
Got to be realistic.
得現實點
Roger... I love you.
Roger... 我愛你
I love you too.
我也愛你
Roger, no!
Roger 別!
So how are we gonna get Aaron now?
我們現在要怎麼救Aaron?
And dad.
還有我爸
Yeah, that's right.
是 沒錯
We're gonna go get your grandfather.
我們要去救你外公
If either of you have any bright ideas, I'd love to hear them.
如果你們有誰有好主意我洗耳恭聽
So here's what we've learned.
我們瞭解的是
Self-healing occurs as a direct reaction to physical trauma,
自愈是對肉體創傷的一種直接反應
like a lizard regrowing its tail...
就像小壁虎長尾巴...
but your defensive actions,
但你的防禦行為
burning people alive and all that,
把人活活燒死之類的
are a response to emotional stimuli.
是對情緒刺激的一種反應
That's what the next phase is all about.
這就是下個階段的重點
Here you go.
好戲開始了
This one should perk you right up.
這一劑能讓你立刻興奮起來
Aaron!
Aaron!
What are you gonna do?
你要幹什麼?
Sorry. I am,
對不起 迫不得已
but we need to elevate you to a proper emotional state.
但我們需要把你激發到合適的情緒狀態
Then maybe...
然後也許...
maybe you can heal someone else.
也許你能治癒別人
No. Please!
不 求你了!
You said you weren't gonna hurt her.
你說你不會傷害她的
I'll check in in a bit.
我一會兒再回來
This room may not be the safest place to be right now.
待在這間屋子現在不是很安全
Stop!
住手!
No!
不!
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents
-------------------------- 本論壇字幕僅翻譯交流學習之用 禁止任何商業用途否則後果自負 --------------------------